A Guide to the Edward Pendleton Herring papers FA1287
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Institutional Files, 1936-1975; 1
  - Reece (Willits and Voegelin), 1954 (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC) - Recent Social Trends - Survey Under Discussion, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 188)
  - Researches in the Social Sciences on Japan, Columbia University East Asian Institute Studies, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 189)
  - Japanese Studies in the United States, Prepared by the Social Science Research Council (SSRC)-American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) Joint Committee on Japanese Studies, 1970 February (Box 15, Folder 190)
  - Outline, The Growth of the Democratic Idea, Pendleton Herring, James Perkins and Charles Frankel, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 191)
  - Agenda, Social Science Research Council (SSRC), Meeting of the Board of Directors, Skytop, Pennsylvania, 1969 September 7-10 (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - 2nd Corning Conference, 1961 May 18-20 (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Carnegie Corporation - Dinner Meeting on Public Administration Materials for Underdeveloped Countries, 1954 March 15 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Hazen Foundation, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Ford Foundation - Clippings, 1953-1955 (Box 15, Folder 196)
  - Ford Foundation - Correspondence and Recommendations, 1951-1968 (Box 15, Folder 197)
  - Notes and Letters, Latin America, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - Notes and Letters, Latin America, 1950-1962 (Box 16, Folder 199-206)
    1962 Council on Higher Education in the American Republics (CHEAR) Conference, Latin American Fulbright Information, Report on the Institute of Political Education Costa Rica, Inter-American Institute for Science and Engineering, CHEAR Report - Visit to Mexico and South America July 8-September 5, 1961, Brookings Insitute Reports, and Clippings
  - Notes and Letters, Latin America, 1950-1962 (Box 17, Folder 207-209)
  - Mexico City, 1962 July 3-4 (Box 17, Folder 210)
  - International Science Panel of the President's Science Advisory Committee, 1963-1967 (Box 17, Folder 211)
  - Department of State - National Commission for UNESCO, 1947-1951 (Box 17, Folder 212)
  - Department of State - National Commission for UNESCO, 1947-1951 (Box 17, Folder 212A)
  - Civil Defense - Project East River, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 213)
  - Elliott Committee, 1964 February (Box 17, Folder 214)
  - Advisory Committee on Military History, 1947-1953 (Box 17, Folder 215)
  - Public Personnel Group, 1957-1958 (Box 17, Folder 216)
  - National Military Establishment - Research and Development Board Committee on Human Resources, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 217)
    Contains 1949 Master Plan for Research and Development in the Defense Department
  - Bureau of the Budget - Committee on Records of War Administration, 1946-1952 (Box 17, Folder 218)
  - National Military Establishment Operations Research Office, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 219)
  - Civil Information and Education Section, War Department, Assignment Offer, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 220)
  - Executive Branch, Salary Stabilization Board, 1947-1952 (Box 18, Folder 221)
  - National Military Establishment Operations Research Office, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 222)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1946-1967 (Box 18, Folder 223)
- General Correspondence, 1945-1970; 2
  - Phone Call Summaries, Aides Memoire, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 224)
    Pertaining to the Social Science Research Council
  - Phone Call Summaries, Aides Memoire, 1953-1957 (Box 18, Folder 225)
  - Applicants and Personnel - A-F, 1948-1960 (Box 21, Folder 255)
    Restricted - Personnel records
  - Applicants and Personnel - G-Z, 1947-1958 (Box 21, Folder 256)
  - A, 1945-1970 (Box 18, Folder 226)
    Correspondence with Harry Alpert, Department of Agriculture, Association of Research Libraries, Hamilton Fish Armstrong, American Academy of Arts and Letters, American Association of University Women Educational Foundation, American Center for Students and Artists, Kathleen Archibald, Gabriel Almond, The Asia Foundation, American Jewish Committee, American Universities Field Staff, University of Arkansas, Association of the United States Army, Australian National University, American Council of Learned Societies
  - B, 1945-1970 (Box 18, Folder 227)
    Correspondence with S. M. Burke, Henry L. Bretton, Zbigniew Brzezinski, Ballantine Books, Inc., Bennington College, Eric Biddle, E.W. Burgess Fund Committee, Eveline Burns, and others
  - C, 1945-1970 (Box 18, Folder 228)
    Correspondence with Bob Carr, Carnegie Hero Fund Commission, William Chambers, Angus Campbell, Laurence Channing, John R. Campbell, Jr., Lynton K. Caldwell, Chinese Students' Christian Association, CBS Television, Communist Party USA, and others
  - Chase, Stuart, 1948-1965 (Box 18, Folder 229)
  - D, 1945-1970 (Box 18, Folder 230)
    Correspondence with Dictionary of American Biography, Dartmouth College, Paul T. David, James C. Davies, Lewis Dexter, Duke University, Marshall E. Dimock, and others
  - E, 1945-1970 (Box 18, Folder 231)
    Correspondence with Eastman Kodak Company, Stanislaw Ehrlich, Alan J. A. Elliott, Rupert Emerson, Rowland Egger, Ferdinand Eberstadt, Herbert Emmerich, Encyclopedia Brittanica, and others
  - F, 1945-1970 (Box 18, Folder 232)
    Elliott P. Fagerberg, John Hope Franklin, Max Fiks, J. W. Fulbright, and others
  - Frankel, Charles, 1961-1970 (Box 18, Folder 233)
  - G, 1945-1970 (Box 19, Folder 234)
    Correspondence with Isabel Grossner, Stanley T. Gordon, John Galbraith, Mary-Joan Gerson, Lewis Galantiere, John W. Gardner, The Gallup Organization, Inc., Erwin Griswold, and others
  - Garceau, Oliver, 1946-1968 (Box 19, Folder 235)
  - H, 1945-1970 (Box 19, Folder 236)
    Correspondence with James H. Hester, J. Hugh Herring, Richard A. Humphrey, Samuel T. Huntington, Louis Hartz, Stephen Hess, Willard Hurst, Norman A. Hilmar, Richard H. Heindel, John C. Honey, John B. Howard, Claude E. Hawley, Charles Hagan, Haskins Laboratories, Paul C. Howard, and others
  - Hasluck, Paul, 1948-1955 (Box 19, Folder 237)
  - I, 1945-1970 (Box 19, Folder 238)
    Correspondence with Institut for Hohere Studien, International Law Commission for Permanent World Peace, International Aviation and Aerospace Exposition, Institute of American Studies in Paris, James Irving, and others
  - J, 1945-1970 (Box 19, Folder 239)
    Correspondence with the Institute of Japanese-American Cultural Research, Inc., Eugene Jacobson, Henry M. Jackson, Roger H. Jones, Don Jacobs, W. K. Jordan, Joseph E. Johnson, and others
  - Josephs, Devereux C., 1953-1955 (Box 19, Folder 240)
  - K, 1945-1970 (Box 19, Folder 241)
    Correspondence with James M. Kiss, Herbert Kaufman, Kentucky Research Foundation, Kenyon College, Alfred A. Knopf, Alexander King, and others
  - V. O. Key, Jr., 1946-1963 (Box 19, Folder 242)
  - L, 1945-1970 (Box 19, Folder 243)
    Correspondence with Theodore Lowi, Arthur Larson, US Department of Labor, Edward Litchfield, Joseph LaPalombara, Alfred Law, Lehigh University, and others
  - Mcc, 1945-1970 (Box 19, Folder 244)
    Correspondence with Joseph E. McLean, Stuart A. MacCorkle, Dayton McKean, Richard McCormick, and others
  - M, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 245)
    Correspondence with Roscoe C. Martin, Malcolm Moos, Tetsuo Misumi, Louis Morton, Henry Allen Moe, Roy Macridis, William H. Masterson, Hugh Moore, Alfred Metraux, Neal Miller, Robert M. Matteson, Fritz Morstein Marx, Michigan State University, Mills College, Harvey C. Mansfield, Paul Mandelstam, and others
  - N, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 246)
    Correspondence with Stuart Nagel, National Negro Leadership Conference, The National Elementary Principal, National Student Association, New School for Social Research, New York Academy of Sciences, New York University, and others
  - O, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 247)
    Correspondence with University of Oregon, Peter H. Odegard Memorial Committee, Samuel H. Ordway, Jr., Oxford University Press, Peter H. Odegard, and others
  - P, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 248)
    Correspondence with James K. Pollock, Princeton University, David M. Potter, Phi Beta Kappa, William Proximore, Public Affairs Committee, Inc., Robert L. Peabody, Charles H. Peake, John A. Perkins, Roy V. Peel, J. Roland Pennock, University of Pennsylvania, Albert Pratt, Public Opinion Quarterly, University of Puerto Rico, and others
  - James Perkins, 1960-1970 (Box 20, Folder 249)
  - R, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 250)
    Correspondence with Dankwart A. Rustow, Albert H. Rosenthal, Ogden Reid, William Robbins, J. Austin Ranney, James M. Reid, Henry W. Riecken, University of Rochester, J. W. Rupley, Rutgers University, and others
  - S, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 251)
    Richard M. Scammon, Paul Seabury, Francis X. Sutton, Robert Saudek, Shepard Stone, David S. Seeley, Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., Donald B. Straus, Albert Somit, Joseph J. Spengler, Rhoten A. Smith, Harold Stein, Syracuse University, Dewey B. Stuit, Smith College, Stanford University, Saturday Review of Literature, Roger W. Shugg, Wilbur Schramm, Harold Smith, and others
  - T-U, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 252)
    Correspondence with United Nations, John Useem, UNESCO representatives, Conrad Taeuber, Harry S. Truman Library, Inc., Twentieth Century Fund, and others
  - W, 1945-1970 (Box 20, Folder 253)
    Correspondence with University of Washington, Wayne State University, Joe Willits, A. T. M. Wilson, Edwin B. Wilson, James J. Wadsworth, Dwight Waldo, C. Vann Woodward, Benjamin F. Wright, Malcolm M. Willey, Washington University, Wellesley College, World Peace Foundation, Charles E. Walgreen Foundation, and others
  - Recent General Letters, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 254)